# Andrés Camilo Zúñiga-González

Accomplished researcher at the postgraduate level with a passion for data-driven insights. Strong background in statistical modelling and scientific research. Focused on knowledge creation based on analytical reasoning. Currently, PhD student at the University of Cambridge applying computational methods to understand how green infrastructure impacts sustainability and health in cities.

Last updated December 2024

ancazugo@hotmail.com

Colombia & UK









#### **SKILLS**

- R (Tidyverse, Shiny), Python (Scikitlearn, Tensorflow, Pytorch), Java, Javascript (D3.js), HTML5, CSS, LaTeX, UNIX Shell, SQL, Spark, Git, Docker, API REST, AWS, ArcGIS and QGIS.
- Data analysis and visualization, machine learning and web development
- Teamwork, group and project management, public speaking and technical writing

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Cartography | Esri
- Data Science For All | Correlation One
- Tensorflow Developer | Deeplearning.ai
- Tensorflow: Data and Deployment | Deeplearning.ai
- Deep Learning | Deeplearning.ai
- Data Science | Johns Hopkins University
- Discrete Mathematics | National Research University Higher School of Economics

## **LANGUAGES**

- Native Spanish
- Fluent English (IELTS C1)
- Limited proficiency in French and Portuguese

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### University of Cambridge, UK

Teaching Supervisor | Oct 2024 - present

Supervise small groups of students on maths and programming.

#### DataLeik, Colombia

Data Scientist | Dec 2021 - Aug 2022

Develop machine learning models for customer segmentation and duplicate detection for Home Capital, a proptech. Deploy web applications via cloud services.

Data Analyst | Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Web scrape real state marketplaces for further integration in a DBMS. Develop interactive visualization tools for data exploration and modelling.

#### Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Research Assistant | Aug 2017 - Feb 2022

Worked on Bayesian modelling of carbon-14 dates of volcano eruptions and human settlements. Research on environmental DNA and chemical markers of high-altitude wetlands from Colombia.

Teaching Assistant | Aug 2017 - Jun 2021

Taught courses in using R and the Linux Command Shell in statistical analysis in research. Developed weekly lectures, activities and exams geared towards students from engineering and science majors.

#### Cornell University, USA

Research Assistant | Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Worked at the Bergstrom Lab in the modelling and statistical analysis of the epidemiological assessment of the Switchgrass Head Smut in the State of New York.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Cambridge, UK

- Ph.D. in AI for Environmental Risk (AI4ER) | present
- M.Res. Environmental Data Science | 2023

#### Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

- M.Sc. in Biological Sciences Biology Focus | 2019
- B.Sc. in Biology | 2016
- B.Sc. in Microbiology | 2016
- Minor in Geography | 2016